{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "Barbara Jordan and Zell Miller gave keynote addresses during party national conventions held in this specific location. In 1982, Sun Myung Moon held the first Blessing Ceremony of the Unification Church outside of Korea in this location, conducting a mass wedding in which 2,500 people were married. The Hulu Theater at this location is currently slated for demolition as part of plans to expand nearby Penn Station. For ten points, identify this New York City concert hall and sporting venue named for the fourth president.",
      "answer": "Madison Square Garden or MSG"
    },
    {
      "question": "This period of time provides the nickname of the queen Elizabeth Stuart, the eldest daughter of James I. During this period of time in 1947, Manny Shinwell was vilified by the British public for failing to maintain adequate supplies of coal. The headline “Crisis? What crisis?” ran during an instance of strife named after this period of time, during which James Callaghan’s government instituted pay caps and lost an election to the Conservative Party under Margaret Thatcher. For ten points, what period “of discontent” names a blizzard-filled season in 1979?",
      "answer": [
        "winter",
        "Winter Queen",
        "Winter of Discontent"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This man won a mayoral race on the ticket of the Family Party, which began his lifelong feud with the leader of the rival Amalgamators, James Buchanan. This man cast a tie breaking vote to pass the Walker Tariff, effectively destroying his reputation in his home state of Pennsylvania, though he was popular as vice president for supporting the annexation of Texas. For ten points, name this politician who was James Polk’s running mate and who probably is not the namesake of a Texas city founded in the 1840s.",
      "answer": "George M. Dallas"
    },
    {
      "question": "A girl from this country named Malalai [ma-la-LIE] became a flag-bearer and inspired her side to victory in the Battle of Maiwand against a British/Indian force. An invasion of this country ended with only the surgeon William Brydon returning across the Hindu Kush range. This country was ruled by the Durrani Dynasty until 1826, and then was the site of three British invasions as part of the “Great Game.” For ten points, name this nation where the British were forced to make an 1842 retreat from Kabul.",
      "answer": "Islamic Republic of Afghanistan"
    },
    {
      "question": "Some of Jean Sibelius’s final works were written for this institution, including an opus 113 suite and an arrangement of Finlandia with new lyrics. Three basset horns are included in the score for a piece of “funeral music” written for this organization. A member of this organization, Emmanuel Schikaneder, wrote the libretto for an opera featuring the Queen of the Night and the bird-catcher Papageno. The composer of The Magic Flute, Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, was a member of the Beneficience Lodge of, for ten points, what Enlightenment-inspired fraternal organization?",
      "answer": [
        "Freemasons",
        "anything related to Masonic lodges, etc."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "During this war, William Inglis famously urged “Die hard, 57th, die hard!” while lying wounded at the Battle of Albuera. One leader’s triumph at the Battle of Vitoria accelerated the end of this war; that leader had built the secret Lines of Torres Vedras as fort chains to defend a territory. The Battle of Salamanca was a major defeat for the forces of Joseph I during this war. A revolt that occurred on May 2, 1808 triggered, for ten points, what war between Napoleon and the Spanish and Portuguese?",
      "answer": "Peninsular War"
    },
    {
      "question": "Simon Metcalfe massacred inhabitants of this kingdom in Olowalu before his assistants John Young and Isaac Davis went to work for its king. Men and women were forbidden from eating together by this kingdom’s kapu system of taboos. This kingdom’s founder protected citizens during wartime with the Law of the Splintered Paddle. Lorrin Thurston helped write this kingdom’s Bayonet Constitution, and he later overthrew its Queen Liliuokalani. For ten points, name this kingdom that was unified after the conquest of Oahu.",
      "answer": "Kingdom of Hawaii"
    },
    {
      "question": "Catherine Green may have fixed design flaws in an invention by this man, but was given no public credit. Fones McCarthy created an updated version of an invention by this man that would handle long-staple resources. Despite no experience and the recent loss of his factory to a fire, this man agreed to make 10,000 muskets for Congress. The boils and lint were separated by a device created by, for ten points, what proponent of interchangeable parts and inventor of the cotton gin?",
      "answer": "Eli Whitney"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the eighth of this poem’s nine sections, “The Spinning-Wheel,” a woman becomes angry when her fianc´ee likens her to Bertha the Beautiful Spinner. A woman in this poem asks “Why don’t you speak for yourself” when a man delivers his best friend’s proposal of marriage to her. This poem imagines a love triangle between John Alden, Priscilla Mullens, and its title character. For ten points, name this Henry Longfellow poem about a romance in Plymouth Colony.",
      "answer": "The Courtship of Miles Standish"
    },
    {
      "question": "This war included the Battle of Norfolk, a tank battle fought the day after the Battle of 73 Easting. The health effects of this conflict were investigated in the Riegle Report, which concluded that soldiers were exposed to chemical weapons. A stretch of road in this conflict was named the “Highway of Death,” as many soldiers were killed trying to retreat to the Euphrates. Norman Schwarzkopf led coalition troops in, for ten points, what early 1990’s war in response to an invasion of Kuwait?",
      "answer": [
        "First Persian Gulf War",
        "First Iraq War",
        "Operation Desert Storm",
        "prompt on Operation Desert Shield"
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "At a battle in this body of water, the Mainz was sunk by a fleet under Reginald Tyrwhitt. That first naval battle of the First World War was held in a bight of this body of water. In this body of water, Admiral Rozhestvensky failed to offer lifeboats after attacking a trawler fleet that was mistakenly thought to be part of the Japanese Navy. In a 1916 battle in this body of water, John Jellicoe defeated a German fleet. The Dogger Bank incident took place in, for ten points, what sea bordering the United Kingdom and Scandinavia?",
        "answer": "North Sea"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "John Jellicoe’s victory over the Germans in the North Sea occurred in this 1916 battle, named for a Danish peninsula.",
        "answer": "Battle of Jutland"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Basil Hart claimed that this man was the first “modern general” in history. The forces of Leonidas Polk were defeated in a campaign led by this man that ended with the capture of Meridian. This man accepted the surrender of Joseph Johnston’s forces at Bennett Place in North Carolina. This general, who allegedly came up with the saying “war is hell,” sent a telegram offering 25,000 bales of cotton as part of a Christmas present after a campaign that was meant to “make Georgia howl.” For ten points, name this Union general who led a March to the Sea.",
        "answer": "William Tecumseh Sherman"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Sherman’s troops carried out a scorched-earth campaign during the March to the Sea, including making so-called “neckties” out of these objects.",
        "answer": [
          "railroads",
          "descriptions of the metal from railroad tracks"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man negotiated a prison exchange that resulted in the return from England of a man who eventually succeeded him, Georgy Chicherin. Before heading to France, this man lived on a Turkish island for four years under the surveillance of Ataturk’s police. The Revolution Betrayed was written by this man. Ram´on Mercader was a Spanish NKVD agent who delivered a fatal blow to this man with an ice-axe during an assassination attempt in Mexico. For ten points, name this leftist Russian revolutionary who created the Red Army.",
        "answer": "Leon Trotsky"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "As this group walked out of the 1917 All-Russian Congress of Soviets, an infuriated Trotsky yelled “Go where you belong - into the dustbin of history!” This faction’s name derives from the Russian for “minority.”",
        "answer": "Mensheviks or Menshevists"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "According to Josephus, this location was originally constructed by Alexander Jannaeus. Defenders at this location may have drawn lots to determine who would kill whom, avoiding a prohibition against suicide. Flavius Silvia built a massive ramp to bypass this location’s “snake” path. This location was defended by the Sicarii, who had earlier fled Jerusalem. For ten points, name this Judean mountaintop fortress that was captured in the waning days of the First Jewish-Roman War.",
        "answer": [
          "Masada",
          "Metsada"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This Roman leader of Judea built a fortress palace on the plateau at Masada roughly a century before the siege. In the Bible, he ordered the Massacre of the Innocents.",
        "answer": "Herod the Great or Herod I"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This organization’s “Equation Group” was targeted in 2016 by The Shadow Brokers. The “EternalBlue” exploit was created by this organization and used to launch the WannaCry ransomware attack. In 2015, this organization was sued by the Wikimedia Foundation, who stated its Upstream collection violated the 1st and 4th Amendments. A subcontractor for this organization leaked information to Glenn Greenwald in 2013. For ten points, name this American intelligence agency whose secrets were leaked by Edward Snowden.",
        "answer": [
          "National Security Agency",
          "NSA"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Edward Snowden leaked the existence of this surveillance program, which has been described as the number one source of raw Internet data for the agency. The FISA Court supervises this program.",
        "answer": "PRISM"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "As a result of this event, the Cameronians suppressed the Dundee Rebellion at the Battle of Dunkeld. Members of the MacDonald clan were killed in the Glencoe Massacre for failing to swear loyalty to a king installed in this event; that king won the Battle of the Boyne and was a stadtholder from the House of Orange. The 1689 English Bill of Rights was passed after this event, which removed the Catholic James II. For ten points, name this bloodless revolution in which William III and Mary II became rulers of England.",
        "answer": [
          "Glorious Revolution",
          "Bloodless Revolution before “bloodless” is mentioned",
          "English Revolution of 1688"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Glorious Revolution is annually celebrated by Protestants on July 12th in a holiday originating in this Irish province. The six counties of Northern Ireland make up two-thirds of this historical province.",
        "answer": "Ulster"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The expansion of Three Rivers Ranch was investigated as part of this event. Thomas Walsh’s lack of seniority left him saddled with investigating this event. As a result of this event, Congress gained the power to compel testimony in McGrain v. Daughtery. Edward Doheny contributed to this scandal by acquiring a lease on Elk Hills in order bolster his petroleum company. Leases of Navy oil fields were the subject of, for ten points, what scandal that rocked the Harding administration?",
        "answer": "Teapot Dome scandal"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Teapot Dome Scandal was orchestrated by this Secretary of the Interior, who possibly murdered Albert Jennings Fountain and his 8 year old son years earlier.",
        "answer": "Albert Fall"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "An ornament found in the tomb of Zhou Chu from the 3rd century mysteriously consists almost entirely of this metal. The first recorded extraction of this metal was in 1825 by Christian Oersted, who heated its chloride with potassium. In industry, this metal is usually extracted by using the Hall-H´eroult process. Karl Bayer discovered a way to refine this metal’s oxide from bauxite. For ten points, name this most abundant in the Earth’s crust, a metal often used in soda cans.",
        "answer": "aluminum"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The cap of this 555-foot tall obelisk is a 100-ounce piece of aluminum, cast two years before development of the Hall-H´eroult process made aluminum significantly cheaper.",
        "answer": "Washington Monument"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "Antebellum Legislation",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "“Bleeding” state where Border Ruffians engaged in violence over popular sovereignty.",
          "answer": "Kansas"
        },
        {
          "question": "Law that criminalized aiding an escaped slave and inspired massive civil disobedience.",
          "answer": "Fugitive Slave Act of 1850"
        },
        {
          "question": "Group of laws drafted by Henry Clay that admitted California as a free state.",
          "answer": "Compromise of 1850"
        },
        {
          "question": "1828 tariff that enraged the South and inspired Calhoun’s Exposition and Protest.",
          "answer": "Tariff of Abominations"
        },
        {
          "question": "Laws that gave citizens land in the West for no cost, in exchange for developing it.",
          "answer": "Homestead Acts"
        },
        {
          "question": "Failedlawthatwouldhavepreventedtheextensionofslaveryinnewly-acquiredterritoryfromMexico.",
          "answer": "Wilmot Proviso"
        },
        {
          "question": "Fertilizer whose presence on an island allowed U.S. citizens to seize that island, according to an 1856 law.",
          "answer": "guano"
        },
        {
          "question": "1850 speech given on the floor of the Senate by William Seward that fiercely decried slavery.",
          "answer": "“Higher Law” speech"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Italian Risorgimento",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Italian general who led the Redshirts during the Risorgimento.",
          "answer": "Giuseppe Garibaldi"
        },
        {
          "question": "First King of united Italy, known as the “Father of the Fatherland.”",
          "answer": [
            "Victor Emmanuel II",
            "Vittorio Emmanuele II"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "1860 event in which the Redshirts traveled to Marsala to conquer the Kingdom of the Two Sicilies.",
          "answer": "Expedition of the Thousand"
        },
        {
          "question": "Italian statesman who eventually took office as the first Prime Minister of Italy, but died after only three months in office.",
          "answer": "Count of Cavour or Camillo Benso"
        },
        {
          "question": "Prominent Risorgimento leader who founded the Young Italy movement.",
          "answer": "Giuseppe Mazzini"
        },
        {
          "question": "1814 conference that resulted in the division of Italy into independent states, eventually prompting the Risorgimento movement.",
          "answer": "Congress of Vienna"
        },
        {
          "question": "Italian nationalist group whose name comes from the Italian for “charcoal,” eventually replaced by the Young Italy movement.",
          "answer": "Carbonari"
        },
        {
          "question": "Commodity that was banned with gambling in 1848, triggering the “Five Days of Milan.”",
          "answer": [
            "tobacco",
            "equivalents"
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Middle Eastern Cities",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Holiest city of Islam, in western Saudi Arabia.",
          "answer": "Mecca or Makkah"
        },
        {
          "question": "Burial place of Muhammad and ancient capital of his empire, the second-holiest city in Islam.",
          "answer": "Medina or Madinah"
        },
        {
          "question": "City in the UAE where modern slave labor built the Burj Khalifa and other skyscrapers.",
          "answer": "Dubai"
        },
        {
          "question": "Financial center of Israel from which the US embassy is slated to be moved.",
          "answer": "Tel Aviv"
        },
        {
          "question": "Capital city on the Persian Gulf where Al Jazeera was launched in 1996.",
          "answer": "Doha"
        },
        {
          "question": "Syrian city where the al-Madina Souq was devastated in the civil war.",
          "answer": "Aleppo"
        },
        {
          "question": "Iranian home of the Pink Mosque, built during the Qajar dynasty.",
          "answer": [
            "Shiraz",
            "Pars"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "City in Iraqi Kurdistan whose namesake citadel was sieged by the Mongols for 6 months in 1258?",
          "answer": [
            "Erbil",
            "Hawler",
            "Arbil",
            "Irbil"
          ]
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Adam Lemp founded a brewery in this city, where he introduced Lager Beer. Marguerite Scypion filed one of the first “freedom suits” in this city. During the Civil War, Nathaniel Lyon captured a state militia at Camp Jackson that was planning to attack this city’s arsenal. Auguste (20 pts)",
        "Chouteau helped found this city, where Minoru Yamasaki built the Pruitt-Igoe housing project. In this city, one of the first bridges that utilized (10 pts)",
        "caissons was built by James Eads to cross the Mississippi River. For ten points, name this city where Eero Saarinen built the Gateway Arch."
      ],
      "answer": "St. Louis"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) During this war, the “Red Prince” led a charge of several hundred freed Chinese slaves with Jose Francisco Gana. The winner of this war demanded the Tarapaca Province at the Lackawanna Conference. During this war, captain (20 pts)",
        "Miguel Grau sank the Esmerelda at the Battle of Iquique, but lost his ironclad Huascar at the Battle of Angamos. This war, which began over a tax dispute near (10 pts)",
        "Antofagasta, was ended by the Treaty of Ancon. For ten points, name this South American war that pitted Peru and Bolivia against Chile over mineral reserves in the late 19th century."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "War of the Pacific or Guerra del Pacifico",
        "Saltpeter War"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A sculptural personification of this location shows a bearded man pulling a cloth from his head. Another depiction of this location found in the remains of Rome’s Campus Martius shows sixteen babies to represent its (20 pts)",
        "yearly floods. This river appears with representations of the Ganges, Rio de la Plata and Danube in the (10 pts)",
        "Fountain of the Four Rivers by Bernini and in another sculpture in the Vatican collection with crocodiles and hippos on its pedestal. A statue dedicated to Isis in the Temple of Peace showed, for ten points, what Egyptian river?"
      ],
      "answer": "Nile River"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Prince Xerxes defeated this man’s forces at the Battle of Thannuris in the Iberian War. This man fought over the region of Lazica with Khosrau the Great, with whom he signed the Treaty of Eternal Peace. During this man’s reign, the (20 pts)",
        "Blues and Greens began riots over chariot races in the Nika Revolt. This Emperor’s generals Narses and (10 pts)",
        "Belisarius reconquered Italy from the Ostrogoths. For ten points, Theodora married which Byzantine Emperor who built the Hagia Sophia and ordered the creation of a namesake law code?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Justinian the Great",
        "Justinian I"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) ‘Anas ibn Malik noted that some of the fallen at the Battle of ‘Uhud had broken this practice; he noted that Allah revealed that no blame would be attached if “they fear Allah and believe and do righteous deeds.” The caliph Umar criticized “the Sword of God,” Khalid ibn al-Walid, for breaking this practice while (20 pts)",
        "taking baths. The “joy of all Rus” [roose] would have violated this practice, and so Vladimir the Great chose not to (10 pts)",
        "convert his people to a certain religion. Khamr is the subject of, for ten points, what religious proscription that Jahangir often broke, as he was fond of brandy?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Islamic ban on consuming alcohol",
        "Khamr before mentioned",
        "equivalents for each of the three underlined parts, including any specific type of alcohol"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This book states that “that which is not ‘body’ is no part of the universe,” supporting a corporeal view of God. In a feud with its author, bishop John Bramhall published a tract about the “Catching of” this book. This book, which was begun while its author taught (20 pts)",
        "mathematics to a young Charles II in Paris, calls ignorance of scripture the “Kingdom of (10 pts)",
        "Darkness.” This book’s first section, “Of Man,” argues that the state of nature is characterized by the war of all against all. For ten points, name this book that argues for strong monarchies by Thomas Hobbes."
      ],
      "answer": "Leviathan or, The Matter, Forme and Power of a Commonwealth Ecclesiastical and Civil"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man once asked Daniel Webster to read a note that stated John Chambers, not James Wilson, would be governor of Iowa. Following one speech, in which the editor noted that he had “killed seventeen Roman proconsuls,” this man went to a (20 pts)",
        "ball at Carusi’s Saloon. As the Democratic Party cast this person as a man who would “sit in his log cabin drinking hard cider,” this man attacked his opponent as (10 pts)",
        "“VanRuin.”ThelongestPresidential inaugural address in history was delivered by, for ten points, what President who was succeeded by John Tyler after he died one month into his term?"
      ],
      "answer": "William Henry Harrison"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Henrik Bergh defended this client, who was accused of ordering the execution of Gunnar Eilifsen. This man, who was also accused of smuggling rubles with Frederik Prytz, worked with Fridtjof Nansen to alleviate the 1921 (20 pts)",
        "Russian famine. This leader worked with the Nazi Reichskommissar Josef Terboven. After King Haakon VII fled, this Nasjonal (10 pts)",
        "Samling leader became head of his country with the support of the Nazis. For ten points, name this collaborationist Norwegian leader whose name is now synonymous with the word “traitor.”"
      ],
      "answer": "Vidkun Quisling , but be lenient"
    }
  ]
}